Contact

+91 9807777735 (Mobile) gopal.tiwari2012@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ gopaltiwari2012 (LinkedIn) dzone.com/users/2730125/ gopaltiwari2012.html (Blog) github.com/gopal-tiwari (Other) gopal-tiwari.github.io/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Apache Spark

Java

Apache Kafka

Languages

English

Hindi

Certifications

MCSA: Web Applications

MS: Programming in C# Specialist

MCPS: Microsoft Certified

Professional

MS: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 Specialist

MS: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web

Applications

Honors-Awards

Awarded Honorable Mention in "International Innovative Application Competition"

Secured 2nd position in IBM National Software Demonstration Competition

Selected in Top 18 Software Projects of India

Above And Beyond

Great Investment Idea Award

Publications

Build and Install Hadoop on Windows with Native Binaries Running Kafka On Windows

Gopal Tiwari

Big Data Developer at VISA Inc.

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Summary

BigData | Spark 2 | Scala | Kafka | Hadoop | Streaming | ElasticSearch | Kibana | Cassandra | Hive | Impala

Adroit Open Source and Big Data enthusiast working as Senior Software Engineer with VISA Inc., having an experience of more than 6.10 years in product development with scala, java & c#.

Advanced technical experience on ETL solutions for Big Data using Apache Spark, Kafka, Hive, Impala, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana and Cassandra.

Having proclivity towards learning new technologies and languages. Loves exploring new languages & technologies. Always finds time to blog key ideas that I discovered while solving challenging problems.

Experience

Visa

Senior Software Engineer

October 2018 - Present

Bengaluru Area, India

Create and optimize the ETL flow to process data stored in Hive, based on the requirements from product office. Write code in Scala with Spark framework, Unit tests, and Manage git pull requests. Tuning & optimization of Spark memory & cores is one of the critical task for this project due to huge data volume ~150 Billion Records with ~6 TB on disk size.

IQVIA

Application Development Specialist November 2016 - September 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Extracting insights from TB's of data collected at medical transactional level. Ex. Prescription adherence of a patient, his choice of medical plan, majority or plurality stores etc.

To create query builder & framework to validate, upload, schedule and process data stored in Hive, based on criteria provided in config Code is primarily written in Scala using Spark. Tuning & optimization of Spark memory & cores is one of the critical tasks for this project due to huge data volume.

Infosys

2 years 10 months

Senior Systems Engineer April 2016 - November 2016 (8 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana, Kafka, Visualizations of Dashboards, Metric computation ETL coding for streaming data with Spark Streaming and Kafka. Develop Spark streaming application to show real-time metric on dashboard along with Kafka administration, extract Metric from Cassandra and Kafka, Spring Rest, Front End & Web Sockets.

Systems Engineer February 2014 - March 2016 (2 years 2 months) Bangalore

Bizz Shine Infosystem Pvt. Ltd. Software Developer July 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 8 months) Lucknow Area, India

Application development responsibilities for front-end, back-end & database development which involves technologies like ASP.NET jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, SignalR, ADO.NET and MS SQL Server.

Education

Uttar Pradesh Technical University

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science &

Engineering · (2008 - 2012)